[{"question":"If the traffic light turns yellow as you enter the intersection, you should:","options":["stop, check traffic, then proceed.","proceed with caution.","stop and back up over the crosswalk.","stop immediately."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"proceed with caution."},{"question":"A yeild sign at an intersection means:","options":["yield to pedestrians only.","yield to approaching traffic.","stop and proceed when safe.","accelerate to clear the intersection."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"yield to approaching traffic."},{"question":"When in a vehicle, seatbelts or safety restraints must be used:","options":["only if required by local bylaw.","when driving on a highway only.","by all occupants for whom a seatbelt is provided.","by front seat occupants only."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"by all occupants for whom a seatbelt is provided."},{"question":"You must have a valid driver's licence to operate a motor vehicle in Saskatchewan:","options":["except when driving down back alleys.","at all times.","only when your vehicle is being operated on primary highways.","unless accompanied by a person over 18."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"at all times."},{"question":"When you have to stop in your driving lane in heavy traffic, you should:","options":["stop any place that is convenient.","stop as close as possible to the car in front of you.","honk your horn first.","always stop before entering an intersection or before a railway crossing."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"always stop before entering an intersection or before a railway crossing."},{"question":"It is illegal to drive at a slow rate of speed on a highway:","options":["when driving in poor visibility","when the roadway is slippery.","when blocking the normal and reasonable movement of traffic.","when driving on a four-lane highway."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"when blocking the normal and reasonable movement of traffic."},{"question":"While driving in dense traffic (rush hour) you should:","options":["maintain at least a three-second following distance between you and the vehicle ahead.","drive close to the vehicle ahead to keep other vehicles from cutting in.","drive close to the vehicle ahead and be ready for a sudden stop.","maintain a three-second following distance if the roads are slippery."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"maintain at least a three-second following distance between you and the vehicle ahead."},{"question":"If your vehicle's turn signals don't work and you plan on making a right turn, what is the proper hand signal?","options":["Left arm positioned downward outside the window at a 90 degree angle.","Left arm positioned outside the window, straight out.","Left arm positioned outside the left window, upward at a 90 degree angle.","Right arm positioned out to the right."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Left arm positioned outside the left window, upward at a 90 degree angle."},{"question":"Lighted arrows are sometimes used to control turns from a specific traffic lane. A yellow arrow is:","options":["Only used on one-way streets.","Never used as a traffic signal.","The same as a green arrow.","A warning that oncoming traffic may next receive a green signal."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"A warning that oncoming traffic may next receive a green signal."},{"question":"Using fraudulent ID or loaning your ID for fraudulent purposes may result in:","options":["all answers are correct.","a fine under the Traffic Safety Act.","a requirement to attend an interview with SGI.","a fraud conviction under the Criminal Code of Canada."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"Changing more than a single lane at one time:","options":["requires one signal but a shoulder check through each lane.","does not require extra attention.","requires only one shoulder check and only one signal.","is never allowed."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"requires one signal but a shoulder check through each lane."},{"question":"According to the law, who is responsible for ensuring passengers under the age of 16 wear their seatbelt or safety restraint?","options":["The passenger's parents, only if the child is under 18 kg (80 lbs).","The passenger's parent or legal guardian.","The driver.","The passenger."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"The driver."},{"question":"The seat belt should be adjusted so that:","options":["the lap belt is buckled snugly and low over your pelvis and the shoulder belt is snug across your chest.","it is hidden beneath the seat.","it keeps the seatbelt warning sound or light from operating.","it is loose."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"the lap belt is buckled snugly and low over your pelvis and the shoulder belt is snug across your chest."},{"question":"When approaching an intersection with a red flashing overhead pedestrian sign, you must:","options":["slow down and proceed when safe.","stop and proceed when safe.","continue through the intersection if there are no pedestrians.","sound the horn to make pedestrians aware that you are there."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"stop and proceed when safe."},{"question":"When turning left:","options":["you must yield the right of way to any vehicle coming towards you.","you have the right of way.","you must yield to emergency vehicles only.","you must look for a sign that allows it."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"you must yield the right of way to any vehicle coming towards you."},{"question":"When you approach an intersection, and the intersection is blocked with traffic. You should:","options":["proceed into the intersection until the traffic moves ahead.","keep as close as possible to the car ahead.","stop before the intersection, wait for traffic to clear, then proceed if safe to do so.","sound horn to warn cars ahead to move on."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"stop before the intersection, wait for traffic to clear, then proceed if safe to do so."},{"question":"If you are involved in a collision with another vehicle, you should:","options":["if you are involved in a collision outside of Saskatchewan, you must provide information on the company that insures your vehicle.","provide your name and address to any other person involved in the collision.","record the licence plate number of all vehicles involved in the collision.","all answers are correct."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"A flashing 'don't walk' means pedestrians should:","options":["not cross but finish crossing the street if they have already started.","stop where they are.","take a chance and walk across the street","walk across the street."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"not cross but finish crossing the street if they have already started."},{"question":"Because you want to see and be visible when driving in the winter, always:","options":["drive with your headlights on.","ensure your windows are clear.","brush the snow off your vehicle.","all answers are correct."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"You should never pass in the oncoming lane:","options":["on the crest of a hill","before a curve.","at intersections.","all answers are correct."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"Where should your vehicle be when you start making a right turn?","options":["any available lane.","as far right as possible.","the left-hand lane.","anywhere on the right side."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"as far right as possible."},{"question":"U-turns are not allowed at:","options":["an intersection with marked traffic lanes.","traffic lights with no signs.","streets with a boulevard.","an intersection controlled by stop signs."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"traffic lights with no signs."},{"question":"When two vehicles approach a 4-way stop intersection at right angles at the same time:","options":["the vehicle on the main road has the right-of-way.","the vehicle on the right has the right-of-way.","both vehicles can proceed.","the vehicle on the left has the right-of-way."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"the vehicle on the right has the right-of-way."},{"question":"Before getting into your vehicle to back up you should:","options":["check to the front only.","check your rear-view mirror only.","check to the sides only.","check around your vehicle from the outside."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"check around your vehicle from the outside."},{"question":"A controlled-access highway or freeway means traffic can:","options":["leave or enter at any place.","leave or enter in light traffic only.","leave or enter at places with shallow ditches.","leave or enter at places indicated."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"leave or enter at places indicated."},{"question":"Driver inattention and distraction lead to collisions. An inattentive driver:","options":["All answers are correct.","talks on a cellphone while driving.","eats, drinks or grooms while driving.","focuses on something in the vehicle like the radio or climate controls."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"All answers are correct."},{"question":"When driving on unpaved (grid/gravel) roads:","options":["Accelerate quickly when passing vehicles.","Stay close to the vehicle in front of you.","Drive on the left side to avoid dust clouds.","Stay back from dust, drive slowly and look up."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Stay back from dust, drive slowly and look up."},{"question":"You are on a through street approaching an uncontrolled 'T' intersection and observe a car approaching from your right, you must:","options":["speed up to cross ahead of the other car.","yield to the car on your right.","yield only if the other car is within the intersection.","come to a complete stop and proceed when safe."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"yield to the car on your right."},{"question":"You must produce your driver's licence and vehicle registration at the request of a police officer.  If you do not have them with you, you may be allowed:","options":["up to 48 hours to produce them.","up to 12 hours to produce them.","up to 72 hours to produce them.","up to 18 hours to produce them."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"up to 48 hours to produce them."},{"question":"You may use a shared centre turn lane:","options":["to turn left to access properties mid-block.","during peak hours only.","to make an emergency stop.","to pass another vehicle on the left."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"to turn left to access properties mid-block."},{"question":"Of all your senses, the most important for driving is:","options":["hearing.","eyesight.","smell","touch"],"answer":"","correct_answer":"eyesight."},{"question":"If you are convicted of driving a motor vehicle with a blood alcohol content equal to or over .08 BAC and under .16 BAC which of the following consequences is true?","options":["A 60 day vehicle impoundment.","A court fine.","A court fine plus a $500 penalty under the Safe Driver Recognition Program.","A court fine plus a minimum $1,250 penalty under the Safe Driver Recognition Program."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"A court fine plus a minimum $1,250 penalty under the Safe Driver Recognition Program."},{"question":"A blind spot is:","options":["the area directly behind your vehicle.","the areas around your vehicle that you cannot see in any of your mirrors.","the area immediately in front of your vehicle.","the area on the passenger side of your vehicle."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"the areas around your vehicle that you cannot see in any of your mirrors."},{"question":"Which of the following road markings allow passing on a highway? ","options":["A double solid line.","A solid line.","A solid and broken line if the solid line is on your side of the highway.","A broken line."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"A broken line."},{"question":"When parking uphill on the side of a road with a curb, the wheels should be:","options":["it doesn't matter in which way the wheels are turned.","turned away from the curb.","turned toward the curb.","not turned at all and remain straight."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"turned away from the curb."},{"question":"It is advisable to back into a parking spot because:","options":["your windows are clear (i.e.free from snow and ice) and you are prepared for driving.","after, when you drive out into traffic, you have an excellent view.","the front end swing occurs in the roadway, not between two parked cars.","all answers are correct."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"If your vehicle is moving towards the ditch:","options":["turn your wheel sharply to return to the road as soon as possible.","brake hard to stop going into the ditch too far.","do not brake hard, do not turn the wheel violently.","accelerate to prevent a rollover."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"do not brake hard, do not turn the wheel violently."},{"question":"For safe winter driving, avoid:","options":["letting your gas tank drop below half full.","all answers are correct.","hard braking and fast accelerating.","using automatic speed control (cruise control) on slippery roads."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"A zipper merge:","options":["is never recommended in construction zones","means drivers use both lanes of traffic until the lane ends, and then alternate in 'zipper' fashion into the open lane.","is inefficient and causes traffic to flow very slowly.","means as soon as drivers notice that a lane is ending due to construction, they should all move into a single lane of traffic"],"answer":"","correct_answer":"means drivers use both lanes of traffic until the lane ends, and then alternate in 'zipper' fashion into the open lane."},{"question":"If a traffic light is red, a driver may turn right if:","options":["They stop and wait for a green light.","They slow down and proceed with caution.","They stop and yield to pedestrians and vehicles and no signs indicate 'no right turn on red'.","There is a sign permitting right turns."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"They stop and yield to pedestrians and vehicles and no signs indicate 'no right turn on red'."},{"question":"When an emergency vehicle or a tow truck is stopped on the highway with its lights flashing, drivers approaching must slow down to:","options":["60 km/h.","80 km/h.","90 km/h.","70 km/h."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"60 km/h."},{"question":"A good driver is easily recognized by:","options":["the condition of their car.","the control and courtesy of the driver.","the number of kilometres driven.","the speed they are driving."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"the control and courtesy of the driver."},{"question":"A solid green arrow with a red traffic light means turns are allowed in the direction of the arrow:","options":["Without yielding to vehicles or pedestrians.","if you yield the right of way to vehicles and pedestrians.","at the intersection of a one-way street.","only after coming to a stop and waiting for a green light."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"if you yield the right of way to vehicles and pedestrians."},{"question":"Signal lights and/or brake lights must be used:","options":["only when other traffic is not present.","only when changing lanes or stopping.","only when turning left or right.","only when turning, stopping or changing lanes."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"only when turning, stopping or changing lanes."},{"question":"Failing to shoulder check for traffic before changing lanes:","options":["Is a bad driving habit and may contribute to a collision.","Is alright if you signal your intention.","Is alright if you signal your intention and check your mirrors.","Is alright if you check the rear-view mirror."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Is a bad driving habit and may contribute to a collision."},{"question":"You reach a 'reduce speed ahead' sign. This means:","options":["Slow down only if driving conditions are poor.","Slow drivers should slow down even more.","Maintain your vehicle's speed until after you pass that sign","Immediately begin to reduce your vehicle's speed"],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Immediately begin to reduce your vehicle's speed"},{"question":"When turning left from a one-way street to a two-way street, the turn should be completed into:","options":["any available lane.","the extreme right curb lane.","the same lane as entering a one-way street.","the lane immediately to the right of the centre line."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"the lane immediately to the right of the centre line."},{"question":"To allow a clear view of the road, aftermarket window tinting (darkening) is not allowed:","options":["on the windshield or front side windows.","on any windows.","on the back or side windows.","on the windshield."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"on the windshield or front side windows."},{"question":"The most dangerous drivers on our roads who account for 40% of all fatal collisions in Saskatchewan are:","options":["older drivers.","teenage drivers.","impaired drivers.","underage drivers."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"impaired drivers."},{"question":"Passengers must not:","options":["distract the driver or other road users.","all answers are correct.","crowd the driver.","ride between the driver and the driver's door."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"In the event of a crash, a properly adjusted head restraint reduces injury. If the head restraint is adjustable, it should be adjusted so that:","options":["the pad of the restraint is anywhere between your shoulders and the top of your head.","you do not feel it while driving.","the pad of the restraint supports the back of your head and the top of the restraint is not lower than the top of your head.","the pad of the restraint supports the back of your neck."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"the pad of the restraint supports the back of your head and the top of the restraint is not lower than the top of your head."},{"question":"Within the 'orange zone' (work zone), drivers are required to:","options":["slow down and travel at no more than 80 km/h.","slow down and travel at no more than 40 km/h.","slow down and travel at no more than 60 km/h or the posted speed.","maintain the highway speed but are not allowed to pass other vehicles."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"slow down and travel at no more than 60 km/h or the posted speed."},{"question":"The difference between yellow and white pavement markings are:","options":["white lines permit passing on the highway, while yellow lines do not permit passing.","white lines separate traffic travelling in opposite directions, yellow lines separate traffic traveling in the same direction.","yellow lines separate traffic travelling in opposite directions, white lines separate traffic traveling in the same direction.","white lines do not permit making a left turn while yellow lines do permit a left turn."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"yellow lines separate traffic travelling in opposite directions, white lines separate traffic traveling in the same direction."},{"question":"A Class 7 driver's licence allows a person to drive a light vehicle (car, truck, SUV or regular van):","options":["in rural areas only.","alone with permission for short distances.","when accompanied by a qualified driver.","during daylight hours only."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"when accompanied by a qualified driver."},{"question":"A slow-moving vehicle sign must be displayed on the back of:","options":["road construction machines only.","vehicles normally travelling below 40 km/h.","all farm equipment.","vehicles normally travelling below 80 km/h."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"vehicles normally travelling below 40 km/h."},{"question":"Before passing a car at an urban (city) intersection, a driver must be certain that:","options":["the vehicle being overtaken has stopped.","the driver ahead intends to turn right.","no pedestrians are using the crosswalk.","the driver ahead intends to turn left."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"no pedestrians are using the crosswalk."},{"question":"Driving while impaired by drugs:","options":["is as dangerous as driving while impaired by alcohol.","is not an offence.","is not as dangerous as driving while impaired by alcohol.","is ok if the drugs are prescribed by a doctor."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"is as dangerous as driving while impaired by alcohol."},{"question":"A broken centre line on pavement means:","options":["passing is allowed if clear.","the same as a solid line.","no passing is allowed.","narrow highway ahead"],"answer":"","correct_answer":"passing is allowed if clear."},{"question":"If an emergency vehicle with its flashing lamps and siren activated approaches your vehicle from the front or rear you must:","options":["reduce speed, move to the right and allow the emergency vehicle to go by you.","maintain your vehicle's speed and lane position.","stop your vehicle immediately.","maintain your speed limit and move over to the right."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"reduce speed, move to the right and allow the emergency vehicle to go by you."},{"question":"Signaling your intentions before turning, changing lanes or driving away from a curb:","options":["is required by law.","is not necessary if the action is done slowly.","is necessary only if other traffic is present.","is necessary only during the maneuver, not before."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"is required by law."},{"question":"If your vehicle's brake lights don't work, what is the proper hand signal when you're stopping?","options":["Left arm positioned outside the window, upward at a 90 degree angle.","Right arm positioned straight out to the right.","Left arm positioned outside the window, downward at a 90 degree angle.","Left arm positioned straight out of the left window."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Left arm positioned outside the window, downward at a 90 degree angle."},{"question":"In a parking lot:","options":["a driver leaving a parking space has the right-of-way.","speed limits do not apply.","a driver in a thoroughfare (main roadway) has the right-of-way.","Signaling is not required."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"a driver in a thoroughfare (main roadway) has the right-of-way."},{"question":"The licence plate on your vehicle:","options":["Can be placed on the front of the vehicle.","Can have a plastic cover on it.","Can be covered by snow or mud.","Must be clearly visible and securely attached."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Must be clearly visible and securely attached."},{"question":"Using a handheld cellphone to talk or text while driving:","options":["is allowed if you are over 18 years old.","is a dangerous distraction and is not legal.","is allowed at all times.","is allowed for experienced drivers only."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"is a dangerous distraction and is not legal."},{"question":"When operating a vehicle with a manual transmission, you must:","options":["ensure the vehicle is in gear, not in neutral, when parked.","all answers are correct.","be able to shift gears without looking at the gear shift.","never depress the clutch for extended periods of time."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"Whenever you get into a vehicle that is new to you:","options":["disregard any obvious defects so you do not delay your travels.","don't show your friend that you are unfamiliar with the vehicle.","drive away, all vehicles are similar.","take time to find out where the controls are."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"take time to find out where the controls are."},{"question":"When entering a provincial highway, you must:","options":["go straight through.","yield the right of way to any vehicles travelling on the provincial highway.","turn right only.","yield when turning left."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"yield the right of way to any vehicles travelling on the provincial highway."},{"question":"You are required to complete a driver's examination if you:","options":["have not held a Saskatchewan driver's licence within the past five years","are a new resident, and the licence you hold is from another province, state or country not honoured or recognized in Saskatchewan.","all answers are correct.","wish to change the class of your licence or obtain an endorsement."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"You are approaching an intersection controlled by four-way stop signs. You should","options":["Stop, wait your turn and go when safe.","Stop.","Slow down and only stop if necessary.","Speed up and clear the intersection."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Stop, wait your turn and go when safe."},{"question":"The most important action you can take while driving at night is:","options":["using your high beams at all times.","slow down so you can see a minimum of 12 seconds ahead.","wait until you can see an object clearly before slowing.","using your low beams at all times."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"slow down so you can see a minimum of 12 seconds ahead."},{"question":"While driving on unpaved (grid) roads, you will notice:","options":["there are many T-intersections.","the distance you see may be shorter","there are no shoulders and curves may be sharper.","all answers are correct."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"To move the vehicle smoothly and to save on fuel:","options":["push the accelerator down gradually and wait for the vehicle to build up speed.","push the accelerator down quickly and hold it there.","drive in a lower gear.","push the accelerator down quickly."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"push the accelerator down gradually and wait for the vehicle to build up speed."},{"question":"The correct place to stop a vehicle when driving on a highway is:","options":["anywhere on the right side.","in the left-hand lane.","as far to the right as possible.","in any available lane."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"as far to the right as possible."},{"question":"Two lanes of traffic can make a turn in the same direction:","options":["only if signs or lights indicate either lane may be used.","only if it is a T-intersection.","only if there are two lanes available for turning.","only when leaving a one-way street."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"only if signs or lights indicate either lane may be used."},{"question":"When turning left, the turn must be started from:","options":["the left-hand lane.","any available lane.","anywhere on the right side.","as far to the right as possible."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"the left-hand lane."},{"question":"If your vehicle's right wheel drops off the pavement edge:","options":["drive into the ditch and stop.","hold the steering wheel firmly, allow the vehicle to slow down before re-entering the highway.","release the steering wheel and brake firmly.","re-enter the highway as soon as possible."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"hold the steering wheel firmly, allow the vehicle to slow down before re-entering the highway."},{"question":"When driving in heavy snow or fog, you will have better visibility if:","options":["your four-way flashers are on.","your park lights are on.","your headlights are on low beam.","your headlights are on high beam."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"your headlights are on low beam."},{"question":"Pedestrians on the highway must walk:","options":["on the right-hand side only.","facing the traffic.","so drivers can see them.","anywhere that is convenient."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"facing the traffic."},{"question":"Night driving requires more caution because:","options":["all you can see is what your headlights show.","you often travel farther distances","vehicles travel faster at night.","many vehicles have only one headlight."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all you can see is what your headlights show."},{"question":"White lane markings:","options":["Are the same as yellow lines.","Are used to separate traffic travelling in the same direction.","Are used to separate traffic travelling in the opposite direction.","No answers are correct."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Are used to separate traffic travelling in the same direction."},{"question":"A flashing red traffic light means the same as a:","options":["Stop sign","Caution Sign","Yield Sign","Yellow light"],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Stop sign"},{"question":"When passing snowplows on the highway with warning lights on, drivers must slow down to:","options":["90 km/h.","60 km/h.","80 km/h.","70 km/h."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"60 km/h."},{"question":"The shoulder of a highway is designed for:","options":["an extra driving lane","passing other vehicles.","stopped vehicles, emergency maneuvers or preparing to make a right turn from the highway.","slower moving vehicles."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"stopped vehicles, emergency maneuvers or preparing to make a right turn from the highway."},{"question":"Which statement is true about parking lots?","options":["You do not have to use turn signals in a parking lot.","Many rules of the road that apply to highways and streets also apply to parking lots.","Parking lots do not have any formal rules.","Vehicles driving through the lot must yield to vehicles leaving a parking space."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Many rules of the road that apply to highways and streets also apply to parking lots."},{"question":"The police ask you to provide an alcohol breath sample. If you refuse, you will receive:","options":["A Safe Driver Recognition Program penalty of $1,000.","A Safe Driver Recognition Program penalty of $2,250.","A Safe Driver Recognition Program penalty of $500.","A Safe Driver Recognition Program penalty of $1,500."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"A Safe Driver Recognition Program penalty of $2,250."},{"question":"When driving at speeds under 60 km/h you should signal your intention to turn:","options":["10 metres before turning.","30 metres before turning.","150 metres before turning, same as at higher speeds.","5 metres before turning."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"30 metres before turning."},{"question":"You are driving on a multi-lane street. Ahead, you notice a vehicle in the lane beside you that is stopped for a pedestrian, you should:","options":["pass the vehicle on the left.","not pass the vehicle.","pass the vehicle on the right.","honk your horn before passing slowly."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"not pass the vehicle."},{"question":"Driving while impaired is illegal. Being impaired can result from:","options":["Alcohol.","Legal or prescription drugs.","All answers are correct.","Illegal drugs."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"All answers are correct."},{"question":"The second offence, within a 12-month period, for using a cell phone illegally while driving will result in:","options":["a 7-day vehicle impoundment for any driver.","a 7-day vehicle impoundment for new drivers under 22 years of age.","a 3-day vehicle impoundment for any driver.","a 3-day vehicle impoundment for drivers under 19 years of age."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"a 7-day vehicle impoundment for any driver."},{"question":"The maximum speed limit when passing highway workers (unless otherwise posted) is:","options":["70 km/h.","90 km/h.","60 km/h.","80 km/h."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"60 km/h."},{"question":"Unless otherwise posted, under normal conditions the maximum speed limit on Saskatchewan highways is:","options":["100 km/h.","90 km/h.","60 km/h.","80 km/h."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"80 km/h."},{"question":"When turning left from a two-way street to one-way street, the turn should be completed into:","options":["the extreme left available driving lane.","the right-hand lane.","the same lane as entering a two-way street.","the center lane."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"the extreme left available driving lane."},{"question":"A left turn from a one-way street to a two-way street should be made from a point:","options":["as close as possible to the left edge of the roadway.","near the centre line.","in the same lane as for a right turn.","close to the right-hand lane."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"as close as possible to the left edge of the roadway."},{"question":"When following another vehicle and you are within 100 metres (330 feet):","options":["your headlights must be on high beam.","your headlights may be on high beam if you are on a divided highway.","your headlights must be on low beam.","your hazard lights should be on."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"your headlights must be on low beam."},{"question":"Which statement is true regarding shared centre turning lanes?","options":["these lanes can be used for parking","the centre lane can be used as a passing lane or a driving lane.","left turns from either direction may be made from these lanes.","these lanes do not require extra attention."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"left turns from either direction may be made from these lanes."},{"question":"You are driving on a highway at 100 km/h and wish to turn onto another road. You should signal your intentions:","options":["about 30 metres before the turn, the same as in the city.","about 150 metres before the turn.","anytime prior to turning.","by putting on your hazard lights."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"about 150 metres before the turn."},{"question":"You are approaching an intersection controlled by four-way stop signs. You should:","options":["Speed up and clear the intersection.","Stop, wait your turn and go when safe.","Slow down and only stop if necessary.","Stop."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Stop, wait your turn and go when safe."},{"question":"Each year in Saskatchewan there are nearly 10000 collisions involving wildlife.  What should you do when you see a wildlife sign?","options":["No answers are correct.","Slow down immediately.","Speed up to leave the area as quickly as possible.","Take extra care and be alert to signs of wildlife such as light reflected in animals' eyes."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Take extra care and be alert to signs of wildlife such as light reflected in animals' eyes."},{"question":"When driving in dense traffic, remember to:","options":["not follow the poor examples of other drivers.","continue your search patterns.","All answers are correct.","continue following at a safe distance."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"All answers are correct."},{"question":"When a large truck passes you on the highway, remember to:","options":["drive on the shoulder until it passes.","sound your horn.","hold your wheel firmly and look where you want to go.","speed up."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"hold your wheel firmly and look where you want to go."},{"question":"Ignition interlock is mandatory if:","options":["You have not held a valid driver’s license in 5 years or more","Your conviction was for impaired driving while equal to or over the legal limit for alcohol.","You reach -10 points in the Safe Driver Recognition program.","You are a new driver and receive your first roadside suspension."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Your conviction was for impaired driving while equal to or over the legal limit for alcohol."},{"question":"Highway construction vehicles have the right of way:","options":["when their warning lights are flashing.","Only if maintenance vehicles are on the proper side of the road.","only within city limits.","when they sound their horn."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"when their warning lights are flashing."},{"question":"When two vehicles approach an intersection with no traffic lights or signs, at approximately the same time:","options":["both vehicles must stop.","the vehicle on the main road has the right-of-way.","the vehicle on the right has the right-of-way.","the vehicle on the left has the right-of-way."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"the vehicle on the right has the right-of-way."},{"question":"As you approach an uncontrolled railway crossing you should:","options":["turn on your four-way flashers.","check for approaching trains and be prepared to stop.","check for flashing red lamps.","slow down the track may be rough."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"check for approaching trains and be prepared to stop."},{"question":"If your vehicle goes into a skid (slides sideways), you should:","options":["allow your vehicle to come to a stop.","accelerate.","brake hard to stop the vehicle quickly.","look where you want to go and steer there."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"look where you want to go and steer there."},{"question":"When passing another vehicle, are you allowed to exceed the posted speed limit?","options":["Yes, only while you are passing a 'group' of cars.","No.","Yes, as long as you are not crossing solid or double solid yellow lines.","Yes, whenever you are passing a vehicle."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"No."},{"question":"If you change your name or address, you must:","options":["do nothing.","stop driving.","advise your local police department.","advise SGI within 15 days."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"advise SGI within 15 days."},{"question":"When reversing, where should you be looking?","options":["In the side mirrors.","Straight ahead.","Over your shoulder, through the rear window and at the back-up camera monitor, if the vehicle is equipped with one.","In the rear view mirror."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Over your shoulder, through the rear window and at the back-up camera monitor, if the vehicle is equipped with one."},{"question":"Which of the following can impair your driving ability?","options":["Physical or emotional stress.","Alcohol and drugs.","Fatigue.","All answers are correct."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"All answers are correct."},{"question":"If you cannot see through your windows, you should:","options":["drive slowly.","drive with your head out the window.","not drive.","buy a new vehicle"],"answer":"","correct_answer":"not drive."},{"question":"When overtaking a motorcycle or a bicycle in your lane, a defensive driver should:","options":["pass in the same manner as passing another car.","sound the horn so they will move over.","pass in the same lane.","always pass to the right."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"pass in the same manner as passing another car."},{"question":"To deal with potential hazards the correct procedure a defensive driver would take is:","options":["identify, decide, predict and execute.","identify, decide, execute and predict.","identify, predict, decide and execute.","identify, execute, decide and predict."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"identify, predict, decide and execute."},{"question":"Yellow line markings are used:","options":["No answers are correct","To separate traffic travelling in the same direction","To separate traffic travelling in opposite directions","The same as white lane markings"],"answer":"","correct_answer":"To separate traffic travelling in opposite directions"},{"question":"When is a 3 second following distance not enough?","options":["When there are fewer than two open spaces (gates) .around your vehicle.","If you are following a large truck or van that blocks your view of traffic ahead.","When road conditions are wet or slippery.","All answers are correct."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"All answers are correct."},{"question":"When stopped on a rural highway at night, you must:","options":["ensure your headlights are on low beam.","stop near an intersection.","exit the vehicle.","mark the vehicle with flares, hazard lights or reflectors."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"mark the vehicle with flares, hazard lights or reflectors."},{"question":"When passing a large truck:","options":["always go faster than the speed limit.","do not move in front of the truck immediately after you have passed it.","only pass on a divided highway.","sound your horn."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"do not move in front of the truck immediately after you have passed it."},{"question":"Are you allowed to drive a vehicle in a bicycle-only lane?","options":["yes, at all times","yes, if you yield to pedestrians.","only during daylight hours.","no"],"answer":"","correct_answer":"no"},{"question":"Automatic speed control (cruise control) should not be used:","options":["On unpaved (grid) roads","On wet or slippery roads","All answers are correct","In urban areas"],"answer":"","correct_answer":"All answers are correct"},{"question":"When entering a roundabout:","options":["the vehicle entering the roundabout has the right-of-way.","traffic in the roundabout has the right-of-way.","the driver must take the first exit.","the driver must stop and proceed when safe."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"traffic in the roundabout has the right-of-way."},{"question":"You are driving and it begins to rain heavily. You should:","options":["drive at the posted speed.","drive faster than other traffic.","drive close behind the vehicle ahead.","slow down and make only small and gentle movements with your brake, accelerator and steering wheel."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"slow down and make only small and gentle movements with your brake, accelerator and steering wheel."},{"question":"On big trucks, there are large blind spots called 'no-zones' around the truck. Which of the following No-Zones should you avoid?","options":["The area directly behind the truck.","The area in front of the truck.","The sides of the truck.","All answers are correct."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"All answers are correct."},{"question":"It is the law that:","options":["all answers are correct.","passengers are not allowed to ride between the driver and the driver's door.","passengers must not crowd the driver.","drivers must have a clear view of the road to the front, sides and rear."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"Under the Safe Driver Recognition program, drivers with 25 points in the safety zone:","options":["are unsafe and risky.","get a 25% discount on plate insurance.","get a $500 discount on plate insurance","are assessed a financial penalty."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"get a 25% discount on plate insurance."},{"question":"If a vehicle is being operated in violation of traffic laws it may be seized and impounded by the police:","options":["only if the driver is the owner of the vehicle","even if the driver is not the owner of the vehicle.","only if the driver is an experienced driver and is no longer in the Graduated Driver Licencing Program.","only if the driver is in the Graduated Driver Licencing Program."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"even if the driver is not the owner of the vehicle."},{"question":"A police officer may suspend the driver's licence of an experienced driver for a period of at least 3 days if:","options":["the driver's blood alcohol content exceeds .04 mg/100 ml.","a collision occurs and damage exceeds $1,000","the vehicle being driven is in poor mechanical condition.","a collision occurs and damage exceeds $500."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"the driver's blood alcohol content exceeds .04 mg/100 ml."},{"question":"When vehicles are not travelling within their lane, they are:","options":["holding up the normal flow of traffic.","not a hazard at any time.","preventing collisions from happening.","being driven in a cautious manner."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"holding up the normal flow of traffic."},{"question":"When a pedestrian is using a crosswalk:","options":["you should slow down and sound your horn.","the crosswalk should be marked with a sign.","the pedestrian must yield the right of way.","drivers must yield the right of way."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"drivers must yield the right of way."},{"question":"You may pass another vehicle:","options":["On the shoulder of the highway.","On a curve or a hill because the chance is small that another vehicle is coming.","On the left when it is safe and you are not crossing a solid or double solid line.","When there is a solid or double solid line on either side of your lane and if it's clear ahead."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"On the left when it is safe and you are not crossing a solid or double solid line."},{"question":"When parked facing downhill on the side of a road, the driver needs to:","options":["turn the front wheels toward the curb.","keep the front wheels straight and in line with the rear wheels.","hope for the best.","turn the front wheels away from the curb."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"turn the front wheels toward the curb."},{"question":"You are following a slow-moving vehicle on a two-lane road, where each lane is traveling in the opposite direction. You may:","options":["pass on left if it is safe and legal.","not pass the vehicle.","pass on right using the paved shoulder.","follow closely and honk the horn."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"pass on left if it is safe and legal."},{"question":"Skidding or sliding can result from:","options":["All answers are correct.","Accelerating too quickly.","Steering too sharply.","Hard braking."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"All answers are correct."},{"question":"A flashing red traffic light means:","options":["slow down and proceed with caution.","stop, proceed when safe.","no turns allowed.","a green light will follow."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"stop, proceed when safe."},{"question":"A driver on a highway approaching a school bus which is displaying flashing red stop lamps and stop arm must:","options":["stop five metres away from the bus and not proceed until the lights are turned off.","reduce speed and proceed with caution if children are not crossing the highway","sound the horn to warn the bus driver.","pass well to the left with caution if children are present."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"stop five metres away from the bus and not proceed until the lights are turned off."},{"question":"If a traffic light changes while a pedestrian is still in the crosswalk, who has the right of way?","options":["the pedestrian.","the motorist coming from his right.","the motorist coming from his left.","the motorist approaching the crosswalk."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"the pedestrian."},{"question":"A police officer directing traffic directs you to go through a red light. What should you do?","options":["go on as directed","stop and check with the police officer","make a U-turn and avoid the intersection","wait for the green light"],"answer":"","correct_answer":"go on as directed"},{"question":"When facing a red traffic light:","options":["you are not allowed to turn right.","you may turn right without stopping.","you may turn right if you stop and yield to vehicles and pedestrians.","you may turn right without yielding to vehicles and pedestrians."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"you may turn right if you stop and yield to vehicles and pedestrians."},{"question":"When making a left turn, if you have to stop in the intersection to wait for oncoming traffic:","options":["keep the vehicle parallel to the lane and keep the front wheels straight.","enter the intersection on an angle to increase visibility.","activate your hazard lights.","turn the front wheels to prepare for the turn."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"keep the vehicle parallel to the lane and keep the front wheels straight."},{"question":"When turning right, you should:","options":["move to the right side of your current lane","move close to the right curb or right edge of the road.","turn from the main driving lane.","turn from any lane."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"move close to the right curb or right edge of the road."},{"question":"When a large truck is approaching you on an unpaved (grid) road you should:","options":["activate your hazard lights.","stop.","speed up and pass them quickly.","slow down and pull as far to the right as possible. You may have to stop."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"slow down and pull as far to the right as possible. You may have to stop."},{"question":"If you notice someone on the road who is driving aggressively, the best thing you can do is:","options":["look them directly in the eye.","pull over and let that person pass by you.","block their lane for the safety of others.","sound your horn at them."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"pull over and let that person pass by you."},{"question":"When on the highway and passing highway equipment with warning lights in operation:","options":["slow to 60 km/h, if the equipment is moving or is stopped.","slow to 60 km/h, only if the equipment is moving.","slow to 80 km/h, only if the equipment is moving.","slow to 80 km/h if the equipment is moving or is stopped."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"slow to 60 km/h, if the equipment is moving or is stopped."},{"question":"If you receive a roadside suspension for drug-impaired driving or a Criminal Code conviction, you could be subject to:","options":["vehicle impoundment.","all answers are correct.","SDR penalty.","impaired driving education."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"A solid line on your side of the broken line means:","options":["narrow highway ahead.","passing is allowed if safe.","no passing allowed.","the same as a single broken line."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"no passing allowed."},{"question":"The Anti-lock Braking System (ABS) was designed to help you:","options":["all answers are correct.","avoid sliding while braking.","maintain some steering ability.","keep your vehicle stable during hard braking."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"Airbags are common features in most vehicles. Which statement is true?","options":["Small children should never be put in the front seat of a vehicle equipped with passenger-side airbags.","Airbags deploy on any impact.","If the vehicle is equipped with airbags, wearing a seatbelt is not necessary.","Airbags are most effective in low speed crashes."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Small children should never be put in the front seat of a vehicle equipped with passenger-side airbags."},{"question":"Driving a vehicle in Saskatchewan is:","options":["a responsibility and privilege.","an entitlement.","no answer is correct.","a way of life."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"a responsibility and privilege."},{"question":"When preparing to stop at an intersection controlled with a stop sign:","options":["stop where it is convenient.","stop directly before the crosswalk whether it is clearly marked on the road or not","stop 3 metres into the intersection in a rural area","stop 10 metres before the intersection in the city, 20 metres before the intersection in rural areas."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"stop directly before the crosswalk whether it is clearly marked on the road or not"},{"question":"During the first snowfall, a driver should:","options":["pull over and stop.","drive faster.","not drive their vehicle.","drive slower and increase the following distance."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"drive slower and increase the following distance."},{"question":"When changing lanes to the right, you should check your blind spot:","options":["by turning your head left to see the entire side gate area of your vehicle.","by turning your head right to see the entire side gate area of your vehicle.","by using the right outside mirror.","by using the rear-view mirror."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"by turning your head right to see the entire side gate area of your vehicle."},{"question":"You are the second vehicle in line at a stop sign. Once the first vehicle proceeds through the intersection:","options":["You must stop again at the stop line.","You may go through the intersection slowly without stopping if there is no other traffic.","You can proceed without stopping again only if you're turning right.","You may follow the vehicle ahead without stopping again."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"You must stop again at the stop line."},{"question":"Large trucks make up a large part of our road traffic, therefore, other drivers should keep in mind that they:","options":["all answers are correct.","take longer to stop.","are slow in accelerating.","require more space for turning."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"If the accelerator pedal sticks:","options":["brake hard.","shift to neutral, slow down, pull over, and stop.","aim your vehicle towards the ditch.","all answers are correct."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"shift to neutral, slow down, pull over, and stop."},{"question":"Under normal conditions a safe following distance on the highway is:","options":["at least two seconds.","at least three metres.","at least three seconds.","at least three car lengths."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"at least three seconds."},{"question":"Before you change lanes:","options":["signal, mirror check, shoulder check and change when safe.","decrease speed and give a correct signal.","look in your rear-view mirror while changing lanes.","give the correct signal and lane change."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"signal, mirror check, shoulder check and change when safe."},{"question":"When riding in a vehicle, children weighing under 18 kgs (40 lbs):","options":["may be safely held by a strong adult.","will not be hurt in a collision because they are small.","must be buckled into proper child safety restraints that are fastened to the vehicle.","are allowed to wear an adult sized seatbelt."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"must be buckled into proper child safety restraints that are fastened to the vehicle."},{"question":"What should you do if part of your brake system fails?","options":["Give up, there is nothing you can do.","Push harder on your brakes even if the pedal goes to the floor and use your parking brake if necessary.","Pump your brakes.","Try to lock up the rear wheels."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Push harder on your brakes even if the pedal goes to the floor and use your parking brake if necessary."},{"question":"If a new driver is caught driving with any amount of alcohol or drug impairment, they will be:","options":["suspended at roadside for a minimum of 24 hours.","required to do community service.","suspended at roadside for a minimum of 60 days.","given a warning."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"suspended at roadside for a minimum of 60 days."},{"question":"To avoid losing control of the vehicle skidding or sliding on slippery roads:","options":["adjust your speed to the conditions, look well ahead so you have time to react and avoid sudden movements of the steering wheel.","only drive on roads with a posted speed limit of 60 km/h or less.","look well ahead and maintain the maximum speed allowed.","adjust your speed to the conditions so you have time to make sudden movements of the steering wheel."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"adjust your speed to the conditions, look well ahead so you have time to react and avoid sudden movements of the steering wheel."},{"question":"Drivers who are caught with a Blood Alcohol Content (BAC) exceeding .08 will have their vehicle towed away and impounded for at least:","options":["1 year.","90 days.","30 days.","3 days."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"30 days."},{"question":"As weather conditions worsen, your following distance should:","options":["Increase to three seconds.","Decrease.","Remain the same.","Increase."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Increase."},{"question":"At what distance are you required to dim your headlights (switch to low beam) when meeting an approaching vehicle at night?","options":["1 kilometre.","60 metres.","90 metres","200 metres."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"200 metres."},{"question":"If a driver's licence includes any restrictions:","options":["they can be ignored as they are for head office use only.","they must be obeyed at all times while driving.","they must be followed by all drivers under the age of 18.","contact SGI or any motor licence issuer to have them removed."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"they must be obeyed at all times while driving."},{"question":"To improve the safety and flow of designated traffic such as transit buses and bicycles, certain traffic lanes have been reserved for their use only. Which statement is true?","options":["You are allowed to enter a bus or bicycle lane to make a right turn, access a parking space or enter a lane or driveway.","You are allowed to drive a vehicle in a bus lane if there are no buses in that lane.","You are allowed to drive a vehicle in a bicycle lane during winter months only.","You are never allowed to enter a bus or bicycle lane."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"You are allowed to enter a bus or bicycle lane to make a right turn, access a parking space or enter a lane or driveway."},{"question":"All drivers (except for school bus drivers) have to do this before entering a provincial highway not marked by traffic signs:","options":["stop, whether or not traffic is approaching.","yield the right-of-way to approaching traffic.","stop before entering the paved portion.","slow to not less than 25 km/h."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"yield the right-of-way to approaching traffic."},{"question":"If your vehicle's turn signals don't work and you plan on making a left turn, what is the proper hand signal?","options":["Left arm positioned outside the window, upward at a 90 degree angle.","Left arm positioned outside the window, downward at a 90 degree angle.","Left arm positioned straight out of the left window.","Right arm positioned straight out to the right."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Left arm positioned straight out of the left window."},{"question":"Failure to report a medical condition may result in:","options":["Nothing.","No insurance coverage.","A different class of licence.","An illness."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"No insurance coverage."},{"question":"In Saskatchewan, child safety restraints must be used for small children:","options":["when traveling with parents.","no matter who is transporting them.","if the driver considers it necessary.","if traveling long distances."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"no matter who is transporting them."},{"question":"All drivers under 22 years of age:","options":["must not drive between midnight and 5 a.m.","must not drive with any level of alcohol or drug impairment (zero tolerance).","are restricted to driving with family members only.","need a supervising driver."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"must not drive with any level of alcohol or drug impairment (zero tolerance)."},{"question":"The headlights of your vehicle must be dimmed (low beam):","options":["when driving on a divided highway.","In all weather conditions.","only when meeting another vehicle.","when meeting or following another vehicle."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"when meeting or following another vehicle."},{"question":"When turning left from a one-way street, a driver must turn from:","options":["close to the right hand curb","near the centre line.","the extreme left-hand lane.","any available lane."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"the extreme left-hand lane."},{"question":"Your eyes (where you look) determine the path your vehicle follows, therefore you:","options":["should close your eyes.","steer where you don't want to go.","should look at your steering wheel.","look where you want to go and steer there."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"look where you want to go and steer there."},{"question":"Winter driving calls for special skills such as:","options":["gentle braking.","gentle acceleration.","small, smooth steering movements.","all answers are correct."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"Drivers who receive a roadside suspension who were transporting passengers under 16 years of age are subject to a minimum vehicle impoundment of:","options":["7 days.","15 days.","3 days.","1 day."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"7 days."},{"question":"The main cause of collisions in winter months is:","options":["driving with your headlights on.","reduced visibility.","more traffic on the road.","failing to adjust to existing conditions."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"failing to adjust to existing conditions."},{"question":"A flashing yellow traffic light means:","options":["yield to approaching traffic.","the same as a flashing red traffic light.","reduce speed and proceed with caution.","Stop and wait until the flashing light discontinues."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"reduce speed and proceed with caution."},{"question":"When entering a street, road or highway from a private road, lane or alley, you must:","options":["not stop for pedestrians if there is no sidewalk","honk the horn so approaching vehicles and pedestrians can allow you room","yield the right-of-way to all pedestrians and traffic","drive slowly so approaching vehicles and pedestrians can get out of your way"],"answer":"","correct_answer":"yield the right-of-way to all pedestrians and traffic"},{"question":"When stopping, you should shift to neutral gear:","options":["on slippery surfaces.","during emergencies","all answers are correct.","to stop in a shorter distance."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"The proper procedure to follow when merging onto a freeway is:","options":["increase to freeway speed and enter traffic safely.","stop on the entrance ramp and wait for a gap in traffic.","enter traffic at a slow speed and increase speed once you are on the freeway.","increase faster than freeway speed."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"increase to freeway speed and enter traffic safely."},{"question":"The speed limit means:","options":["the fastest speed a driver is allowed except when passing.","the fastest speed a driver is allowed at all times except at night.","the fastest speed a driver is allowed under all driving conditions.","the fastest speed a driver is allowed under the best conditions."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"the fastest speed a driver is allowed under the best conditions."},{"question":"You should drive with your vehicle’s headlights on:","options":["because it charges your vehicle's battery.","at all times.","when driving small passenger vehicles only.","when operating motorcycles only."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"at all times."},{"question":"You are at an intersection and have the right of way but another driver does not yield to you. What action do you take?","options":["sound your horn to warn the other driver you are proceeding.","continue through the intersection because you have the right of way.","increase your speed.","allow the other driver to proceed to avoid a collision."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"allow the other driver to proceed to avoid a collision."},{"question":"When being passed, always:","options":["flash your lights.","pull over and stop.","allow the vehicle to pass you safely.","speed up."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"allow the vehicle to pass you safely."},{"question":"The traffic ahead has stopped without leaving you sufficient space to cross the intersection. You should:","options":["Enter the intersection anyway.","Reduce speed, check the traffic and then enter the intersection.","Enter the intersection as long as you can cross at least half way.","Stop before entering the intersection, wait for traffic to clear, then proceed if safe to do so."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"Stop before entering the intersection, wait for traffic to clear, then proceed if safe to do so."},{"question":"Pedestrians may not cross an intersection when they are facing:","options":["a 'don't walk' light or symbol.","a red light.","a yellow light.","all answers are correct."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"all answers are correct."},{"question":"Because of a large truck's bigger blind spots, class 5 drivers should always remember to:","options":["leave extra room to allow the truck to maneuver (move).","avoid streets that may have trucks on them.","follow the large truck closely to make passing easier.","pass as soon as possible."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"leave extra room to allow the truck to maneuver (move)."},{"question":"When making a right turn:","options":["you may not turn from the main driving lane.","it is the driver's responsibility to move as close to the right curb, or right edge of the road, as possible.","if a vehicle is parked in the lane closest to the right curb and near the intersection, the driver must move into that lane at the first opportunity before turning.","All answers are correct."],"answer":"","correct_answer":"All answers are correct."}]